<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gtd | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/gtd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-24T23:40:22+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Should I Focus On?]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/05/25/what-should-i-focus-on/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-25T16:46:28+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/05/25/what-should-i-focus-on</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am working again on my goals. I want to be focused and work on the most important things.</p>

<p>In this short post I will share some of the things I have been doing to get myself on the right track again.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<h2>What should I work on?</h2>

<p>This is maybe the most difficult question, but once you get it figured out everything else becomes easier.</p>

<p>In the past I used following system with good results:</p>

<ul>
<li>What do I want to be true when I am 40?</li>
<li>Great, what needs to happen than before I am 30?</li>
<li>And what should I do this year?</li>
</ul>


<p>Recently, I have been introduced by <a href="https://twitter.com/gigantiqandy">Andy</a> to intermediate objective maps. They complement the system I&rsquo;ve been using, by visualising it nicely. I&rsquo;ve created small little tool for myself to make <a href="http://gregdmd.com/iom">creation of intermediate objective maps</a>
 easier.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s3.postimg.org/jbjh5nx03/Screen_Shot_2014_05_25_at_5_24_13_pm.png">http://s3.postimg.org/jbjh5nx03/Screen_Shot_2014_05_25_at_5_24_13_pm.png</a>"></p>

<p> Check it out and let me know what you think.</p>

<p> The best tip Andy gave me was to share my map with my peers and get feedback. I am going to implement this advice soon :)</p>

<p> As a bonus, few weeks back I was wondering how much time actually I have before I am 30, hence this little tool, <a href="http://gregdmd.com/dob">the age calculator</a>.</p>

<h2>What should I work on this week?</h2>

<p>To visualise what I am working on at the moment (and where my attention should be) I&rsquo;ve started using recently <a href="http://trello.com">virtual board</a> provided by Trello.</p>

<p>At the moment my personal kanban board has following columns: &ldquo;Thinking about&rdquo;, &ldquo;To do&rdquo;, &ldquo;Doing&rdquo;, &ldquo;Waiting / Tracking&rdquo; and &ldquo;Done&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s30.postimg.org/qygzfyhtt/Screen_Shot_2014_05_25_at_5_27_28_pm.png">http://s30.postimg.org/qygzfyhtt/Screen_Shot_2014_05_25_at_5_27_28_pm.png</a>"></p>

<p>I am experimenting with the on-line tool for this, as it gives me a lot of flexibility. Trello has a good mobile client and nice web UI.</p>

<h2>What should I work on next week?</h2>

<p>During a normal week I have heaps of interesting thoughts. They are inspired by conversation I have, tweets &amp; blogs I skim over, etc. It&rsquo;s quite easy to move on and forget about them.</p>

<p>To avoid this, I am capturing all those little thoughts and ideas in my &ldquo;Inbox&rdquo; <a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote</a> notebook. Every Saturday I go through my &ldquo;Inbox&rdquo; and I triage the notes. This gives me a chance to action some of them, or at least plan what to do next.</p>

<p>Evernote again is great for this, as it has easy to use mobile client that doesn&rsquo;t get in the way. For triage, Evernote desktop client is efficient and enjoyable to work with.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Hope you are inspired to try some of these ideas out. What tools and techniques are you using to stay focused?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
