<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Github | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/github/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-03T19:06:43+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Launching HeCoSiRe]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/01/04/launching-hecosire/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T12:10:53+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/01/04/launching-hecosire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve launched my new pet project HeCoSiRe and you can be part of it ;)</p>

<p><img src="/images/hecosire.png" alt="HeCoSiRe" /></p>

<p>So what is it about?</p>

<p><strong>Functionally</strong>, the vision is to have a platform to track how you feel and generate insights into your health.</p>

<p><em>Adults get an average of two to four colds per year(<a href="http://www.lung.org/lung-disease/influenza/in-depth-resources/facts-about-the-common-cold.html">source</a>)</em>
I&rsquo;ve got mine over the x-mas break. Not fun, but a good motivation for a pet project.</p>

<p>From <strong>technology</strong> point of view, it&rsquo;s just an excuse to learn more about tools involved (<em>Android, Rails and machine learning + more?</em>).</p>

<p>So how can you get involved?</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Interested in learning about your health?</h2>

<p>You can help by just getting on board, using the tool and providing feedback.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s early days, but you can already easily capture how you feel. Over time I plan to add features around
analysing the data. Maybe one day HeCoSiRe will be able to notice:
<em>every time you start feeling sick and you eat a lemon you actually don&rsquo;t get sick</em>.</p>

<p>There is <a href="http://hecosire.com/">a website hecosire.com</a> where you can create an account.</p>

<p>You can also get an <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=hecosire.com.hecosireapp">Android HeCoSiReApp</a>.</p>

<p>Last but not least, there is a <a href="https://twitter.com/hecosire">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://trello.com/b/iw8dxU8A/hecosire">Trello</a> if you want to interact about the product.</p>

<h2>Interested about technology?</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s a pet project and as much as I am interested in the product I also want to learn how to use tools involved.</p>

<p>For example I am new to Android and I&rsquo;m building an Android app. I am sure the way it&rsquo;s done at the moment it&rsquo;s not the best way to do it.
Overtime I hope to learn and improve, but in the meantime feedback and pull requests are welcomed.</p>

<p>Yes &ndash; HeCoSiRe is open source, you can find it on <a href="https://github.com/hecosire/">HeCoSiRe github</a>.</p>

<p>This also means, that if there is a feature you would like to see in HeCoSiRe, you can add it ;)</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p><em>HeCoSiRe &ndash; what a strange name?</em> Yes I know, I needed something quickly for my &ldquo;rails new&rdquo; ;) It&rsquo;s from &ldquo;<strong>He</strong>althy, <strong>Co</strong>ming down, <strong>Si</strong>ck and <strong>Re</strong>covering&rdquo; cycle that I decided to use in the app.</p>

<p>If you are reading this, next step is to <a href="http://hecosire.com/users/sign_up">create a HeCoSiRe account</a> and start tracking :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hudson.plugins.git.GitException: Failed to Fetch From git@github.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/12/12/hudson-dot-plugins-dot-git-dot-gitexception-failed-to-fetch-from-git-at-github-dot-com/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-12T21:49:26+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/12/12/hudson-dot-plugins-dot-git-dot-gitexception-failed-to-fetch-from-git-at-github-dot-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Problem: Red build</h2>

<p>Unless your Jenkins project just stopped building with this exception <code>hudson.plugins.git.GitException: Failed to fetch from git@github.com</code> you are unlikely to get much of this post ;)</p>

<p>I guess there might be bunch of the reasons why you could see this message, but here is what happend to me..</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>My project hosted on github suddenly started to fail when building in jenkins. Initially I had no clue why and I&rsquo;ve done bunch of google searches:</p>

<p><code>
 jenkins github returned status code 128:
 jenkins ssh keys github stoped working
 "hudson.plugins.git.GitException: Failed to fetch from git@github.com"
</code></p>

<h2>Investigation</h2>

<p>Thinking a little bit more about my situation. We have a Jenkins that is connecting to GitHub using different ssh keys depending on project (<a href="https://developer.github.com/guides/managing-deploy-keys/#deploy-keys">deploy key approach</a> ). So I continued to google:</p>

<p><code>
 jenkins multiple ssh keys not working
 ssh debug which key git is using
</code></p>

<p>That led me to additional debugging commands: <code>ssh -vvvT git@github.com</code> and adding in <code>~/.ssh/config</code></p>

<p>```
  Host github.com</p>

<pre><code>LogLevel DEBUG3
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>While checking out projects from github and looking and debugging output problem became quite clear. Git, while using SSH, was authenticating using incorrect ssh key.</p>

<h2>Solution</h2>

<p>In the end, what happend was that previous day I&rsquo;ve replaced <code>~/.ssh/config</code> on Jenkins box. Among other things, there was a problematic bit of config:</p>

<p><code>
Host *
  ControlMaster auto
  ControlPath /tmp/ssh_mux_%h_%p_%r
  ControlPersist 10m   # - this was causing issues
</code></p>

<blockquote><p>ControlPersist &ndash;  that automatically
  starts a background ssh(1) multiplex master when connecting. This
  connection can <strong>stay alive indefinitely</strong>, or can be set to
  automatically close after a user-specified duration of inactivity</p></blockquote>

<p>Above configuration was causing issues, when different projects were being build on Jenkins that were meant to use different ssh keys (while talking to github).</p>

<p>Removing above config solved the problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
