<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Agile | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/agile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-15T09:23:40+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delivery Engineering Team]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/07/19/delivery-engineering-team/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-19T10:45:59+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/07/19/delivery-engineering-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>What is it?</h2>

<p>One definition could be:</p>

<blockquote><p>Delivery engineering team enables others to deliver business value faster.</p></blockquote>

<p>Others, in this context, relates to product/project software delivery teams.</p>

<p><img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/deleng.jpg"/></p>

<p>It seems to be a fairly new term, judging by the lack of definition in google or a recent tweet from #devopsdays in Melbourne:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Finally an appropriate name for what i actually do - Delivery Engingeering. Thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/devopsdays?src=hash">#devopsdays</a></p>&mdash; griggle (@griggle) <a href="https://twitter.com/griggle/status/621483550974439425">July 16, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://gregdmd.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Another, maybe more common name seems to be <a href="https://www.rallydev.com/blog/engineering/you-don-t-need-devops-team-you-need-tools-team">&ldquo;tooling team&rdquo;</a>.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s definitely not a <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/techniques/separate-devops-team">&ldquo;devops team&rdquo;</a>.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s in?</h2>

<p>In the delivery engineering team, that I am a part of, some of the metrics we are trying to improve are:</p>

<ul>
<li>CI Build time</li>
<li>Deploy time</li>
<li>New server creation time</li>
<li>New production like environment creation time</li>
<li>New developer laptop setup time</li>
</ul>


<p>I guess there are many ways to go about moving above, but in the teams I&rsquo;ve worked with, the day to day often was:</p>

<ul>
<li>Moving software from a legacy platform to a new one. (Think AWS/docker migration)</li>
<li>Creating tools and practices to support the above.</li>
<li>Technology evangelism, training &amp; support for product teams.</li>
</ul>


<h2>What&rsquo;s out?</h2>

<p>The product teams should have full freedom and responsibility to run their apps in production.</p>

<p>So it&rsquo;s not the responsibility of a delivery engineering team to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Upgrade frameworks and libraries used by a product team. The product team itself should do it.</li>
<li>Carry a pager, be on-call as support for production systems (unless those are the systems that delivery engineering team is a custodian of, for example CI server)</li>
<li>Be a gate keeper on a path to production. The product teams themselves can decide what and when to release.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Techniques &amp; Practices</h2>

<p>Some of the techniques and practices important for a delivery engineering team:</p>

<ul>
<li>Team rotation</li>
<li><a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/ContinuousDelivery.html">Continuous Delivery</a></li>
<li>Showcase</li>
</ul>


<h2>Do you need a delivery engineering team?</h2>

<p>Maybe :&ndash;)</p>

<p>You most likely need delivery engineering, and if you are big enough, you may decide to form a team around it. The size I have experience with and seems to work OK, is one small delivery engineering team for roughly three product teams. To use <a href="http://blog.crisp.se/2012/11/14/henrikkniberg/scaling-agile-at-spotify">spotify terminology</a>, delivery engineering team is part of a tribe and supports squads.</p>

<h2>To sum up</h2>

<p>This is based on my experience, what do you think? :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Are you a member of delivery engineering team? What do you think is important to share?</p>

<p>Are you a &ldquo;customer&rdquo; of delivery engineering team, for example a member of product team? What are your toughts on having a delivery engineering team?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[1-1 Feedback Blog Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/09/21/1-1-feedback-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-21T17:45:33+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/09/21/1-1-feedback-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been introduced to one to one team feedback by Pat Kua in 2011. To this date, it&rsquo;s one of my favourited practices in an agile project <em>( I recommend Pat&rsquo;s blog post series you can find <a href="https://www.thekua.com/atwork/2009/10/a-guide-to-receiving-feedback-part-i-ask-for-it/">here</a> )</em>.</p>

<p>During last 12 months or so, I was luckly enough to work in a team that was interested and happy to practice it. Also, teams around me were curious about it and I&rsquo;ve run a few introductory sessions.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>Together with Ilya, I&rsquo;ve written up a short blog post explaining a little bit why and how we have been practicing it. You can find the <a href="http://techblog.realestate.com.au/one-to-one-feedback-at-rea/">blog post here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make It Happen]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/03/25/make-it-happen/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-25T22:11:49+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/03/25/make-it-happen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<em>This is a transcript of a speech I&rsquo;ve delivered recently in my Toastmasters club.</em>)</p>

<p>Two years ago a bus full of employes of 1 company department was heading for a team event. I was sitting on this bus and chatting with a person next to me.</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>“Hey, did you notice that in our department we are quite good at knowledge sharing?”<br/>“You know, we show each other what are we working on, we practice together”<br/>“How about other departments? We don’t share so much with them?”<br/>“Yeah, let&rsquo;s do something about it!”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>and we did.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>If you are working with other people, and sometimes you want to change things then please listen. I would like to share with you 3 simple techniques you can do, to introduce new ideas successfully.</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>We used more techniques than <em>“Brown bag”</em>, <em>“Ask for help”</em> or <em>“Corporate angel”</em>. You can read about those and more in a book by Linda Rising and Mary Lynn Manns called “Fearless change, patterns for introducing new ideas”, I highly recommend this book.</p>

<p>In the end, we managed to organise our conference. It was a great success, with 2 tracks, around 10 speakers and almost 100 people attending. This all started by 2 people having a crazy idea in the bus.</p>

<p>In a big company, two normal workers, like you and me. So if we could do it, you can do it. Go, read the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0201741571/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0201741571&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=gregdziesblog-20">“Fearless change" book</a> and made your ideas happen.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
