<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Agile | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/agile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-09T23:55:28+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make It Happen]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/03/25/make-it-happen/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-25T22:11:49+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/03/25/make-it-happen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<em>This is a transcript of a speech I&rsquo;ve delivered recently in my Toastmasters club.</em>)</p>

<p>Two years ago a bus full of employes of 1 company department was heading for a team event. I was sitting on this bus and chatting with a person next to me.</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>“Hey, did you notice that in our department we are quite good at knowledge sharing?”<br/>“You know, we show each other what are we working on, we practice together”<br/>“How about other departments? We don’t share so much with them?”<br/>“Yeah, let&rsquo;s do something about it!”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>and we did.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>If you are working with other people, and sometimes you want to change things then please listen. I would like to share with you 3 simple techniques you can do, to introduce new ideas successfully.</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>We used more techniques than <em>“Brown bag”</em>, <em>“Ask for help”</em> or <em>“Corporate angel”</em>. You can read about those and more in a book by Linda Rising and Mary Lynn Manns called “Fearless change, patterns for introducing new ideas”, I highly recommend this book.</p>

<p>In the end, we managed to organise our conference. It was a great success, with 2 tracks, around 10 speakers and almost 100 people attending. This all started by 2 people having a crazy idea in the bus.</p>

<p>In a big company, two normal workers, like you and me. So if we could do it, you can do it. Go, read the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0201741571/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0201741571&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=gregdziesblog-20">“Fearless change" book</a> and made your ideas happen.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
