<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Toastmasters | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/toastmasters/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-03T19:06:43+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feel Good About Public Speaking - Thanks to Virtual Reality]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/03/feel-good-about-public-speaking-thanks-to-virtual-reality/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-03T18:15:20+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/03/feel-good-about-public-speaking-thanks-to-virtual-reality</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong> Free Google Cardboard <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">Public Speaking app</a> </strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/publicspeaking.jpg" alt="Public Speaking Cardboard VR" /></p>

<p>Well known fact &ndash; many of us are afraid of speaking in front of an audience.</p>

<p>Actually, many people <strong>put fear of public speaking in front</strong> of things like <strong>death</strong> &ndash; sounds pretty serious :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Did you know, that practicing in front of virtual audience can remove this fear? It may not be obvious at first, but speaking in front of the virtual audience can boost your confidence in a real world.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>There is</strong> some <strong>research to back up</strong> this statement, for example:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Higher perceived audience interest (in VR) increases self-rating and reduces public speaking anxiety.</p><footer><strong>Public Speaking in Virtual Reality: Facing an Audience of Avatars <a href="http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/M.Slater/Papers/g2prjvr.lo.pdf">http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/M.Slater/Papers/g2prjvr.lo.pdf</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>or <a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.217.1498&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf">Virtual Reality Therapy: An Effective Treatment for Psychological Disorders</a>.</p>

<h2>Background</h2>

<p>Few years ago in Toastmasters, I&rsquo;ve learned about the technique that helps me focus on the audience when practicing speech at home.</p>

<p>It involves finding some old magazines with people on the cover and setting them up around the room, so that you are facing a &ldquo;virtual audience&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s not very responsive group of folks, but very patient :&ndash;) Anyway, it help with things like maintaining an eye contact.</p>

<p>Another technique I&rsquo;ve learnt, was &ldquo;positive visualization&rdquo;. Basically, you imagine that you are delivering your speech and the audience is smiling and happy. This in turn, makes you more relaxed and confident when you get to deliver your speech for real.</p>

<h2>Solution with Google Cardboard</h2>

<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve combined what I&rsquo;ve learnt in Toastmasters with the research I&rsquo;ve found on-line. <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">&ldquo;Public Speaking for Cardboard VR&rdquo;</a> was born :&ndash;)</p>

<p>In the app, you are standing in front of the very <strong>receptive and supportive audience</strong>. They look cartoonish which will have a <strong>relaxing effect</strong> on you.</p>

<p>The app helps you learn to maintain an eye contact with members of the audience, by rewarding you every time you do it. Look one of the avatars in the eyes, and he will give you a standing ovation.</p>

<p>Last but not least, because you will be presumably wearing VR goggles, there is no way to rely on notes. By mastering your speech by heart you will be able to keep your audience engaged by maintaining an eye contact throughout the speech.</p>

<h2>Share your experience</h2>

<p>Please share in comments your feedback on the app. How to make it better, more useful for you?</p>

<p>Maybe you had an important speech to deliver and you used the app to practice.. Please comment below and tell us all about it :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Get the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">&ldquo;Public Speaking for Cardboard VR&rdquo;</a> now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dinging Ah-Counter Android App]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/07/19/dinging-ah-counter-android-app/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-19T20:10:58+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/07/19/dinging-ah-counter-android-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Ah-Counter is responsible for noting and keeping track of words and sounds used as a ‘crutch’ or
‘pause filler’ by anyone who speaks during the <a href="http://www.toastmasters.org/Members/MemberExperience/MeetingRoles/Ahcounter.aspx">Toastmasters meeting</a>. Words may be inappropriate interjections such
as <em>and</em>, <em>well</em>, <em>but</em>, <em>so</em>, <em>like</em>, <em>you know</em>. Sounds may be <em>ah</em>, <em>um</em>, <em>er</em>.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>If you are a speaker, at the end of the meeting Ah-Counter will tell you how many times he caught you making inappropriate interjections, for example:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&hellip;<br/>Greg &ndash; 7 times.<br/>Mark &ndash; only 1 time.<br/>&hellip;</p><footer><strong>Ah-Counter</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>This always leaves me wondering: &ldquo;When exactly do I make those sounds?&rdquo;. Reports like this are delivered too late, after I had already finished speaking.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen clubs solve this problem &ndash; Ah-Counter has a ring and uses it anytime he catches you. &ldquo;Ding!&rdquo; and immediately you are reminded to stop making &ldquo;um&rdquo;.</p>

<p>My current assignment is to get a dinging device for my club &ndash;
<a href="http://easy-speak.org/clubdata.php?c=4566"onclick="trackOutboundLink('http://easy-speak.org/clubdata.php?c=4566'); return false;"> Docklands Toastmasters</a>. I&rsquo;ve spent some time today going around shops looking for something like this:</p>

<p><img src="/images/tablebell.jpg" alt="bell" /></p>

<p>but I couldn&rsquo;t find any&hellip; So instead I&rsquo;ve made an app ;)</p>

<p>You can get <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=agilesurfing.pl.dingingahcounter"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=agilesurfing.pl.dingingahcounter'); return false;"> Dinging Ah-Counter Android App for free  </a> here.</p>

<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=agilesurfing.pl.dingingahcounter"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=agilesurfing.pl.dingingahcounter'); return false;">
  <img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/ahcounter.jpg"/>
</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Should I Focus On?]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/05/25/what-should-i-focus-on/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-25T16:46:28+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/05/25/what-should-i-focus-on</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am working again on my goals. I want to be focused and work on the most important things.</p>

<p>In this short post I will share some of the things I have been doing to get myself on the right track again.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<h2>What should I work on?</h2>

<p>This is maybe the most difficult question, but once you get it figured out everything else becomes easier.</p>

<p>In the past I used following system with good results:</p>

<ul>
<li>What do I want to be true when I am 40?</li>
<li>Great, what needs to happen than before I am 30?</li>
<li>And what should I do this year?</li>
</ul>


<p>Recently, I have been introduced by <a href="https://twitter.com/gigantiqandy">Andy</a> to intermediate objective maps. They complement the system I&rsquo;ve been using, by visualising it nicely. I&rsquo;ve created small little tool for myself to make <a href="http://gregdmd.com/iom">creation of intermediate objective maps</a>
 easier.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s3.postimg.org/jbjh5nx03/Screen_Shot_2014_05_25_at_5_24_13_pm.png">http://s3.postimg.org/jbjh5nx03/Screen_Shot_2014_05_25_at_5_24_13_pm.png</a>"></p>

<p> Check it out and let me know what you think.</p>

<p> The best tip Andy gave me was to share my map with my peers and get feedback. I am going to implement this advice soon :)</p>

<p> As a bonus, few weeks back I was wondering how much time actually I have before I am 30, hence this little tool, <a href="http://gregdmd.com/dob">the age calculator</a>.</p>

<h2>What should I work on this week?</h2>

<p>To visualise what I am working on at the moment (and where my attention should be) I&rsquo;ve started using recently <a href="http://trello.com">virtual board</a> provided by Trello.</p>

<p>At the moment my personal kanban board has following columns: &ldquo;Thinking about&rdquo;, &ldquo;To do&rdquo;, &ldquo;Doing&rdquo;, &ldquo;Waiting / Tracking&rdquo; and &ldquo;Done&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s30.postimg.org/qygzfyhtt/Screen_Shot_2014_05_25_at_5_27_28_pm.png">http://s30.postimg.org/qygzfyhtt/Screen_Shot_2014_05_25_at_5_27_28_pm.png</a>"></p>

<p>I am experimenting with the on-line tool for this, as it gives me a lot of flexibility. Trello has a good mobile client and nice web UI.</p>

<h2>What should I work on next week?</h2>

<p>During a normal week I have heaps of interesting thoughts. They are inspired by conversation I have, tweets &amp; blogs I skim over, etc. It&rsquo;s quite easy to move on and forget about them.</p>

<p>To avoid this, I am capturing all those little thoughts and ideas in my &ldquo;Inbox&rdquo; <a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote</a> notebook. Every Saturday I go through my &ldquo;Inbox&rdquo; and I triage the notes. This gives me a chance to action some of them, or at least plan what to do next.</p>

<p>Evernote again is great for this, as it has easy to use mobile client that doesn&rsquo;t get in the way. For triage, Evernote desktop client is efficient and enjoyable to work with.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Hope you are inspired to try some of these ideas out. What tools and techniques are you using to stay focused?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
