<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Android | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/android/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-13T10:43:27+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feel Good About Public Speaking - Thanks to Virtual Reality]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/03/feel-good-about-public-speaking-thanks-to-virtual-reality/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-03T18:15:20+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/03/feel-good-about-public-speaking-thanks-to-virtual-reality</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong> Free Google Cardboard <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">Public Speaking app</a> </strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/publicspeaking.jpg" alt="Public Speaking Cardboard VR" /></p>

<p>A well known fact &ndash; many of us are afraid of speaking in front of an audience.</p>

<p>Actually, many people fear public speaking more then they fear <strong>death</strong> &ndash; sounds pretty serious :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Did you know that practicing in virtual reality can remove this fear? It may not be obvious at first, but speaking in front of a virtual audience can boost your confidence in the real world.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>There is</strong> some <strong>research to back this up</strong>, for example:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Higher perceived audience interest (in VR) increases self-rating and reduces public speaking anxiety.</p><footer><strong>Public Speaking in Virtual Reality: Facing an Audience of Avatars <a href="http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/M.Slater/Papers/g2prjvr.lo.pdf">http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/M.Slater/Papers/g2prjvr.lo.pdf</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>or <a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.217.1498&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf">Virtual Reality Therapy: An Effective Treatment for Psychological Disorders</a> that talks about application of VR to threat phobias.</p>

<h2>Background</h2>

<p>A few years ago in Toastmasters, I&rsquo;ve learned about a technique that helps me focus on the audience when practicing speech at home.</p>

<p>It involves finding some old magazines with people on the cover and setting them up around the room, so that you are facing a &ldquo;virtual audience&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s not a very responsive group of folks, but there are very patient :&ndash;) Anyway, the technique helps with things like maintaining eye contact.</p>

<p>Another tool I&rsquo;ve learned, is &ldquo;positive visualization&rdquo;. Basically, you imagine that you are delivering your speech and the audience is happy and smiling. This, in turn, makes you more relaxed and confident when you get to deliver your speech for real.</p>

<h2>Solution with Google Cardboard</h2>

<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve combined what I&rsquo;ve learned in Toastmasters with the research I&rsquo;ve found on-line. <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">&ldquo;Public Speaking for Cardboard VR&rdquo;</a> was born :&ndash;)</p>

<p>In the app, you are standing in front of a very <strong>receptive and supportive audience</strong>. They look cartoonish which will have a <strong>relaxing effect</strong> on you.</p>

<p>The app helps you learn to maintain eye contact with members of the audience, by rewarding you every time you do it. Look one of the avatars in the eyes, and he will give you a standing ovation.</p>

<p>Last but not least, because you will be presumably wearing VR goggles, there is no way to rely on notes. By mastering your speech by heart you will be able to keep your audience engaged by maintaining eye contact throughout the speech.</p>

<h2>Share your experience</h2>

<p>Please share in comments your feedback on the app. How to make it better? How to make it more useful for you?</p>

<p>Maybe you had an important speech to deliver and you used the app to practice&hellip; Please comment below and tell us all about it :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Get the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">&ldquo;Public Speaking for Cardboard VR&rdquo;</a> now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shipping MarineVerse]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/01/17/shipping-marineverse/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-17T20:21:05+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/01/17/shipping-marineverse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the start of 2016 I&rsquo;ve started working on a new project. <a href="http://www.marineverse.com">MarineVerse &ndash; all about sailing in virtual reality</a>. I am having quite a bit of fun working on it, combining my passion for sailing and technology.</p>

<p>I am working on MarineVerse together with Olga, with a great result. For example, check out the awesome logo :&ndash;)
<a href="http://www.marineverse.com"><img itemprop="image" src="http://blog.marineverse.com/assets/banner.png"/></a></p>

<p>Currently I am using Unity to build simple cardboard apps and also experimenting with GearVR. Below you can see me showing an early version of &ldquo;<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.marineverse.pointofsail">Point of Sail</a>&rdquo; app.</p>

<p><img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/demo_of_point_of_sail.png"/></p>

<p>Also, finally I&rsquo;ve signed up to a sailing club in Melbourne and with a start of Feburary I will be joining a sailing course. Looking forward to it :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Coming back to MarineVerse, I am working on it with full steam ahead. There is a <a href="http://www.marineverse.com">landing page</a> and <a href="http://blog.marineverse.com">blog</a>.</p>

<p>Please <a href="https://twitter.com/MarineVerseVR">follow MarineVerse</a> on twitter and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/MarineVerse/">like it on Facebook</a>. Cheers :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game of Life With Google Cardboard]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/11/15/game-of-life-with-google-cardboard/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-15T08:58:21+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/11/15/game-of-life-with-google-cardboard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol'); return false;">Get Game of Life for Cardboard here.</a></p>

<h2>What is it?</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s pretty much in the name :&ndash;) Have a look at screenshot to get an idea of what it is.</p>

<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol'); return false;"><img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/gol.jpg"/></a></p>

<p>What is special about this &ldquo;Game of life&rdquo; is, that you get to experience it in Virtual Reality, giving you a new, unique perspective.</p>

<p>You can learn <a href="https://www.google.com/get/cardboard/">more about Cardboard here</a> and read about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_Game_of_Life">Game of life on wikipedia</a>.</p>

<h2>How is it made?</h2>

<p>The app is made using <a href="https://unity3d.com/">Unity 5</a>. I&rsquo;ve started learning Unity recently and I am impressed how easy it&rsquo;s to get started. They have good tutorials that get you going and assets store full of things you can use in your apps.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s really simple implementation written in C#, using <a href="https://developers.google.com/cardboard/unity/">SDK</a>.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen a great qoute on VR sometime ago:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Virtual Reality is BY FAR the biggest delta I&#39;ve ever seen between what it looks like from the outside vs what it feels like on the inside.</p>&mdash; Marc Andreessen (@pmarca) <a href="https://twitter.com/pmarca/status/658479467296264192">October 26, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://gregdmd.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>I agree, and what it means is that you really need to get your hands on a Cardboard and try out the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol'); return false;">Game of Life for yourself.</a> :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Launching HeCoSiRe]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/01/04/launching-hecosire/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T12:10:53+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/01/04/launching-hecosire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve launched my new pet project HeCoSiRe and you can be part of it ;)</p>

<p><img src="/images/hecosire.png" alt="HeCoSiRe" /></p>

<p>So what is it about?</p>

<p><strong>Functionally</strong>, the vision is to have a platform to track how you feel and generate insights into your health.</p>

<p><em>Adults get an average of two to four colds per year(<a href="http://www.lung.org/lung-disease/influenza/in-depth-resources/facts-about-the-common-cold.html">source</a>)</em>
I&rsquo;ve got mine over the x-mas break. Not fun, but a good motivation for a pet project.</p>

<p>From <strong>technology</strong> point of view, it&rsquo;s just an excuse to learn more about tools involved (<em>Android, Rails and machine learning + more?</em>).</p>

<p>So how can you get involved?</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Interested in learning about your health?</h2>

<p>You can help by just getting on board, using the tool and providing feedback.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s early days, but you can already easily capture how you feel. Over time I plan to add features around
analysing the data. Maybe one day HeCoSiRe will be able to notice:
<em>every time you start feeling sick and you eat a lemon you actually don&rsquo;t get sick</em>.</p>

<p>There is <a href="http://hecosire.com/">a website hecosire.com</a> where you can create an account.</p>

<p>You can also get an <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=hecosire.com.hecosireapp">Android HeCoSiReApp</a>.</p>

<p>Last but not least, there is a <a href="https://twitter.com/hecosire">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://trello.com/b/iw8dxU8A/hecosire">Trello</a> if you want to interact about the product.</p>

<h2>Interested about technology?</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s a pet project and as much as I am interested in the product I also want to learn how to use tools involved.</p>

<p>For example I am new to Android and I&rsquo;m building an Android app. I am sure the way it&rsquo;s done at the moment it&rsquo;s not the best way to do it.
Overtime I hope to learn and improve, but in the meantime feedback and pull requests are welcomed.</p>

<p>Yes &ndash; HeCoSiRe is open source, you can find it on <a href="https://github.com/hecosire/">HeCoSiRe github</a>.</p>

<p>This also means, that if there is a feature you would like to see in HeCoSiRe, you can add it ;)</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p><em>HeCoSiRe &ndash; what a strange name?</em> Yes I know, I needed something quickly for my &ldquo;rails new&rdquo; ;) It&rsquo;s from &ldquo;<strong>He</strong>althy, <strong>Co</strong>ming down, <strong>Si</strong>ck and <strong>Re</strong>covering&rdquo; cycle that I decided to use in the app.</p>

<p>If you are reading this, next step is to <a href="http://hecosire.com/users/sign_up">create a HeCoSiRe account</a> and start tracking :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dinging Ah-Counter Android App]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/07/19/dinging-ah-counter-android-app/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-19T20:10:58+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2014/07/19/dinging-ah-counter-android-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Ah-Counter is responsible for noting and keeping track of words and sounds used as a ‘crutch’ or
‘pause filler’ by anyone who speaks during the <a href="http://www.toastmasters.org/Members/MemberExperience/MeetingRoles/Ahcounter.aspx">Toastmasters meeting</a>. Words may be inappropriate interjections such
as <em>and</em>, <em>well</em>, <em>but</em>, <em>so</em>, <em>like</em>, <em>you know</em>. Sounds may be <em>ah</em>, <em>um</em>, <em>er</em>.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>If you are a speaker, at the end of the meeting Ah-Counter will tell you how many times he caught you making inappropriate interjections, for example:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&hellip;<br/>Greg &ndash; 7 times.<br/>Mark &ndash; only 1 time.<br/>&hellip;</p><footer><strong>Ah-Counter</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>This always leaves me wondering: &ldquo;When exactly do I make those sounds?&rdquo;. Reports like this are delivered too late, after I had already finished speaking.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen clubs solve this problem &ndash; Ah-Counter has a ring and uses it anytime he catches you. &ldquo;Ding!&rdquo; and immediately you are reminded to stop making &ldquo;um&rdquo;.</p>

<p>My current assignment is to get a dinging device for my club &ndash;
<a href="http://easy-speak.org/clubdata.php?c=4566"onclick="trackOutboundLink('http://easy-speak.org/clubdata.php?c=4566'); return false;"> Docklands Toastmasters</a>. I&rsquo;ve spent some time today going around shops looking for something like this:</p>

<p><img src="/images/tablebell.jpg" alt="bell" /></p>

<p>but I couldn&rsquo;t find any&hellip; So instead I&rsquo;ve made an app ;)</p>

<p>You can get <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=agilesurfing.pl.dingingahcounter"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=agilesurfing.pl.dingingahcounter'); return false;"> Dinging Ah-Counter Android App for free  </a> here.</p>

<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=agilesurfing.pl.dingingahcounter"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=agilesurfing.pl.dingingahcounter'); return false;">
  <img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/ahcounter.jpg"/>
</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
