<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vr | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/vr/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-13T10:43:27+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My 6 Favorites Demos From Vision Summit 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/13/my-6-favorites-demos-from-vision-summit-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-13T10:22:31+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/13/my-6-favorites-demos-from-vision-summit-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/vs2016.png" alt="Vision Summit" /></p>

<p>Vision Summit 2016 is probably my craziest conference trip to date. It took 25000 kilometres in distance and over 30 hours of travel just to attend 2 days event. Did I mention that I decided to go and bought all my tickets 5 days before? Yes, it was pretty crazy :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Was it worth it? Hell yeah! It was a huge VR conference, with over 1000 participants and lots of cool things to see :&ndash;) .. Plus, apparently all devs taking part in the event are going to receive free HTC Vive dev kit &ndash; nice surprise!</p>

<!--more-->


<p>In my opinion, the best quote of the conference goes to Jeff Noris from NASA, when he was talking about possible future applications of VR in space exploration:
<blockquote><p>sorry to tell this will not be the future &ndash; this is happening today</p></blockquote>
Watch the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2hYDtxCtzdA">full keynote</a> to experience it.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2hYDtxCtzdA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I would like to share with you 3 demos I enjoyed the most. What they have in common, is that I was able to forget about VR hardware and just enjoy the experience. The list:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Tilt Brush with HTC Vive</strong> &ndash; it’s mind blowing :&ndash;) Being able to paint in 3D with your hands and walk around your art work is something you can only do in VR. And it’s fun.</li>
<li><strong>The London Heist with PlayStation VR</strong> &ndash; my first time with PlayStation VR &ndash; positively surprised by quality of the experience. The game itself was so fun to play. Being able to lean outside the window in a running car and shot is pretty cool. If you have Playstation 4 &ndash; you have to get Playstation VR.</li>
<li><strong>Lucky&rsquo;s Tale with Oculus Rift</strong> &ndash; This was just pure joy to play. Being able to lean forward or sideways is surprisingly fulfilling when playing 3D platformer. Looking forward to playing games like SimCity or Civilization.</li>
</ul>


<p>And 3 more demos, that I really liked:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Arch Virtual</strong> &ndash; this is the future of architecture and interior design. Let me just say &ndash; you are inside a kitchen, and with a few gestures you can change colour of wall paint, type of tiles or pick a model of a fridge &ndash; and see in the real time effects of your decisions. This is better than, and will replace construction show rooms.</li>
<li><strong>Budget Cuts</strong> -I was not good at it, so I didn’t enjoyed this game as much. However, I really would like to come back to it. Stealth mode games are perfect fit for VR and this one is very well made. Playing something like Comandos would be great.</li>
<li><strong>Virzoom</strong> &ndash; gym bike + VR. That combination works really well. I expect to see that in the gyms very soon.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you haven’t yet tried latest generation of VR hardware on well made content, like mentioned above &ndash; you have to try.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/tj0Zw2Q0wbE/maxresdefault.jpg" alt="Mind blown" /></p>

<p>Your mind might be blown away and you have to experience it to understand what I mean.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feel Good About Public Speaking - Thanks to Virtual Reality]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/03/feel-good-about-public-speaking-thanks-to-virtual-reality/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-03T18:15:20+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/03/feel-good-about-public-speaking-thanks-to-virtual-reality</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong> Free Google Cardboard <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">Public Speaking app</a> </strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/publicspeaking.jpg" alt="Public Speaking Cardboard VR" /></p>

<p>A well known fact &ndash; many of us are afraid of speaking in front of an audience.</p>

<p>Actually, many people fear public speaking more then they fear <strong>death</strong> &ndash; sounds pretty serious :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Did you know that practicing in virtual reality can remove this fear? It may not be obvious at first, but speaking in front of a virtual audience can boost your confidence in the real world.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>There is</strong> some <strong>research to back this up</strong>, for example:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Higher perceived audience interest (in VR) increases self-rating and reduces public speaking anxiety.</p><footer><strong>Public Speaking in Virtual Reality: Facing an Audience of Avatars <a href="http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/M.Slater/Papers/g2prjvr.lo.pdf">http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/M.Slater/Papers/g2prjvr.lo.pdf</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>or <a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.217.1498&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf">Virtual Reality Therapy: An Effective Treatment for Psychological Disorders</a> that talks about application of VR to threat phobias.</p>

<h2>Background</h2>

<p>A few years ago in Toastmasters, I&rsquo;ve learned about a technique that helps me focus on the audience when practicing speech at home.</p>

<p>It involves finding some old magazines with people on the cover and setting them up around the room, so that you are facing a &ldquo;virtual audience&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s not a very responsive group of folks, but there are very patient :&ndash;) Anyway, the technique helps with things like maintaining eye contact.</p>

<p>Another tool I&rsquo;ve learned, is &ldquo;positive visualization&rdquo;. Basically, you imagine that you are delivering your speech and the audience is happy and smiling. This, in turn, makes you more relaxed and confident when you get to deliver your speech for real.</p>

<h2>Solution with Google Cardboard</h2>

<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve combined what I&rsquo;ve learned in Toastmasters with the research I&rsquo;ve found on-line. <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">&ldquo;Public Speaking for Cardboard VR&rdquo;</a> was born :&ndash;)</p>

<p>In the app, you are standing in front of a very <strong>receptive and supportive audience</strong>. They look cartoonish which will have a <strong>relaxing effect</strong> on you.</p>

<p>The app helps you learn to maintain eye contact with members of the audience, by rewarding you every time you do it. Look one of the avatars in the eyes, and he will give you a standing ovation.</p>

<p>Last but not least, because you will be presumably wearing VR goggles, there is no way to rely on notes. By mastering your speech by heart you will be able to keep your audience engaged by maintaining eye contact throughout the speech.</p>

<h2>Share your experience</h2>

<p>Please share in comments your feedback on the app. How to make it better? How to make it more useful for you?</p>

<p>Maybe you had an important speech to deliver and you used the app to practice&hellip; Please comment below and tell us all about it :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Get the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.publicspeaking">&ldquo;Public Speaking for Cardboard VR&rdquo;</a> now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shipping MarineVerse]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/01/17/shipping-marineverse/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-17T20:21:05+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/01/17/shipping-marineverse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the start of 2016 I&rsquo;ve started working on a new project. <a href="http://www.marineverse.com">MarineVerse &ndash; all about sailing in virtual reality</a>. I am having quite a bit of fun working on it, combining my passion for sailing and technology.</p>

<p>I am working on MarineVerse together with Olga, with a great result. For example, check out the awesome logo :&ndash;)
<a href="http://www.marineverse.com"><img itemprop="image" src="http://blog.marineverse.com/assets/banner.png"/></a></p>

<p>Currently I am using Unity to build simple cardboard apps and also experimenting with GearVR. Below you can see me showing an early version of &ldquo;<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.marineverse.pointofsail">Point of Sail</a>&rdquo; app.</p>

<p><img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/demo_of_point_of_sail.png"/></p>

<p>Also, finally I&rsquo;ve signed up to a sailing club in Melbourne and with a start of Feburary I will be joining a sailing course. Looking forward to it :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Coming back to MarineVerse, I am working on it with full steam ahead. There is a <a href="http://www.marineverse.com">landing page</a> and <a href="http://blog.marineverse.com">blog</a>.</p>

<p>Please <a href="https://twitter.com/MarineVerseVR">follow MarineVerse</a> on twitter and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/MarineVerse/">like it on Facebook</a>. Cheers :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CampJS Project - ArtSocks VR]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/11/24/campjs-project-artsocks-vr/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-24T07:56:51+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/11/24/campjs-project-artsocks-vr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend I&rsquo;ve been to <a href="http://vi.campjs.com/">CampJS</a>.</p>

<p>It was 4 days event held on a camp site in Queensland, Australia. Imagine mixture of conference, hackathon and social event. It works great and I highly recommend this format :&ndash;) ( Checkout the <a href="https://twitter.com/search?f=images&amp;vertical=default&amp;q=%23campjs&amp;src=typd">photos on twitter</a> )</p>

<p>Thank you everyone who made CampJS a blast :&ndash;)</p>

<h2>ArtSocks VR</h2>

<p>During the weekend I&rsquo;ve decided to experiemnt with virtual reality in the browser.</p>

<p><a href="https://art-socks.herokuapp.com/demo.html"><img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/art-socks.jpg"/></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve used <a href="https://github.com/borismus/webvr-boilerplate">webvr-boilerplate</a> to build simple virtual art gallery prototype.</p>

<p>To make it more fun, I&rsquo;ve used websockets so you can be in the gallery with someone else.</p>

<p>Below list of images I&rsquo;ve used in the demo:</p>

<ol>
<li> <a href="http://www.redbubble.com/people/cardboardcities/works/12292601-hydrangea-polka?ref=home_found">hydrangea polka</a></li>
<li> <a href="http://www.redbubble.com/people/jenni40947/works/17071969-autumn-leaves-teal?ref=home_found">Autumn Leaves (Teal)</a></li>
<li> <a href="http://www.redbubble.com/people/oparina/works/17493280-parallel-universe?ref=home_found">Parallel Universe</a></li>
<li> <a href="http://www.redbubble.com/people/mloyan/works/15375385-june-and-her-crocodile?ref=home_found">june &amp; her crocodile</a></li>
<li> <a href="http://www.redbubble.com/people/tofuvi/works/17587398-infuse?ref=home_found">infuse.</a></li>
</ol>


<p><a href="https://art-socks.herokuapp.com/demo.html">Please have a look at a demo &ndash; it works the best in VR :&ndash;)</a> (open in browser on the phone and click VR icon)</p>

<p>PS. One of the great things abotu CampJS was ability to show what you are building and get ideas and feedback from people around you. Ben from SceneVR showed me how easy it is to build something similar in SceneVR. It&rsquo;s really cool project, <a href="http://www.scenevr.com">check it out</a> :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game of Life With Google Cardboard]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/11/15/game-of-life-with-google-cardboard/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-15T08:58:21+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/11/15/game-of-life-with-google-cardboard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol'); return false;">Get Game of Life for Cardboard here.</a></p>

<h2>What is it?</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s pretty much in the name :&ndash;) Have a look at screenshot to get an idea of what it is.</p>

<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol'); return false;"><img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/gol.jpg"/></a></p>

<p>What is special about this &ldquo;Game of life&rdquo; is, that you get to experience it in Virtual Reality, giving you a new, unique perspective.</p>

<p>You can learn <a href="https://www.google.com/get/cardboard/">more about Cardboard here</a> and read about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_Game_of_Life">Game of life on wikipedia</a>.</p>

<h2>How is it made?</h2>

<p>The app is made using <a href="https://unity3d.com/">Unity 5</a>. I&rsquo;ve started learning Unity recently and I am impressed how easy it&rsquo;s to get started. They have good tutorials that get you going and assets store full of things you can use in your apps.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s really simple implementation written in C#, using <a href="https://developers.google.com/cardboard/unity/">SDK</a>.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen a great qoute on VR sometime ago:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Virtual Reality is BY FAR the biggest delta I&#39;ve ever seen between what it looks like from the outside vs what it feels like on the inside.</p>&mdash; Marc Andreessen (@pmarca) <a href="https://twitter.com/pmarca/status/658479467296264192">October 26, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://gregdmd.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>I agree, and what it means is that you really need to get your hands on a Cardboard and try out the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol"onclick="trackOutboundLink('https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.agilesurfing.gol'); return false;">Game of Life for yourself.</a> :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
