<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Devops | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/devops/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-15T09:23:40+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delivery Engineering Team]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/07/19/delivery-engineering-team/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-19T10:45:59+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2015/07/19/delivery-engineering-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>What is it?</h2>

<p>One definition could be:</p>

<blockquote><p>Delivery engineering team enables others to deliver business value faster.</p></blockquote>

<p>Others, in this context, relates to product/project software delivery teams.</p>

<p><img itemprop="image" src="http://gregdmd.com/images/deleng.jpg"/></p>

<p>It seems to be a fairly new term, judging by the lack of definition in google or a recent tweet from #devopsdays in Melbourne:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Finally an appropriate name for what i actually do - Delivery Engingeering. Thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/devopsdays?src=hash">#devopsdays</a></p>&mdash; griggle (@griggle) <a href="https://twitter.com/griggle/status/621483550974439425">July 16, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://gregdmd.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Another, maybe more common name seems to be <a href="https://www.rallydev.com/blog/engineering/you-don-t-need-devops-team-you-need-tools-team">&ldquo;tooling team&rdquo;</a>.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s definitely not a <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/techniques/separate-devops-team">&ldquo;devops team&rdquo;</a>.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s in?</h2>

<p>In the delivery engineering team, that I am a part of, some of the metrics we are trying to improve are:</p>

<ul>
<li>CI Build time</li>
<li>Deploy time</li>
<li>New server creation time</li>
<li>New production like environment creation time</li>
<li>New developer laptop setup time</li>
</ul>


<p>I guess there are many ways to go about moving above, but in the teams I&rsquo;ve worked with, the day to day often was:</p>

<ul>
<li>Moving software from a legacy platform to a new one. (Think AWS/docker migration)</li>
<li>Creating tools and practices to support the above.</li>
<li>Technology evangelism, training &amp; support for product teams.</li>
</ul>


<h2>What&rsquo;s out?</h2>

<p>The product teams should have full freedom and responsibility to run their apps in production.</p>

<p>So it&rsquo;s not the responsibility of a delivery engineering team to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Upgrade frameworks and libraries used by a product team. The product team itself should do it.</li>
<li>Carry a pager, be on-call as support for production systems (unless those are the systems that delivery engineering team is a custodian of, for example CI server)</li>
<li>Be a gate keeper on a path to production. The product teams themselves can decide what and when to release.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Techniques &amp; Practices</h2>

<p>Some of the techniques and practices important for a delivery engineering team:</p>

<ul>
<li>Team rotation</li>
<li><a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/ContinuousDelivery.html">Continuous Delivery</a></li>
<li>Showcase</li>
</ul>


<h2>Do you need a delivery engineering team?</h2>

<p>Maybe :&ndash;)</p>

<p>You most likely need delivery engineering, and if you are big enough, you may decide to form a team around it. The size I have experience with and seems to work OK, is one small delivery engineering team for roughly three product teams. To use <a href="http://blog.crisp.se/2012/11/14/henrikkniberg/scaling-agile-at-spotify">spotify terminology</a>, delivery engineering team is part of a tribe and supports squads.</p>

<h2>To sum up</h2>

<p>This is based on my experience, what do you think? :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Are you a member of delivery engineering team? What do you think is important to share?</p>

<p>Are you a &ldquo;customer&rdquo; of delivery engineering team, for example a member of product team? What are your toughts on having a delivery engineering team?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
