<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Conference | Greg Dziemidowicz's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/categories/conference/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregdmd.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-13T10:43:27+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregdmd.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Dziemidowicz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My 6 Favorites Demos From Vision Summit 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/13/my-6-favorites-demos-from-vision-summit-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-13T10:22:31+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregdmd.com/blog/2016/02/13/my-6-favorites-demos-from-vision-summit-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/vs2016.png" alt="Vision Summit" /></p>

<p>Vision Summit 2016 is probably my craziest conference trip to date. It took 25000 kilometres in distance and over 30 hours of travel just to attend 2 days event. Did I mention that I decided to go and bought all my tickets 5 days before? Yes, it was pretty crazy :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Was it worth it? Hell yeah! It was a huge VR conference, with over 1000 participants and lots of cool things to see :&ndash;) .. Plus, apparently all devs taking part in the event are going to receive free HTC Vive dev kit &ndash; nice surprise!</p>

<!--more-->


<p>In my opinion, the best quote of the conference goes to Jeff Noris from NASA, when he was talking about possible future applications of VR in space exploration:
<blockquote><p>sorry to tell this will not be the future &ndash; this is happening today</p></blockquote>
Watch the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2hYDtxCtzdA">full keynote</a> to experience it.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2hYDtxCtzdA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I would like to share with you 3 demos I enjoyed the most. What they have in common, is that I was able to forget about VR hardware and just enjoy the experience. The list:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Tilt Brush with HTC Vive</strong> &ndash; it’s mind blowing :&ndash;) Being able to paint in 3D with your hands and walk around your art work is something you can only do in VR. And it’s fun.</li>
<li><strong>The London Heist with PlayStation VR</strong> &ndash; my first time with PlayStation VR &ndash; positively surprised by quality of the experience. The game itself was so fun to play. Being able to lean outside the window in a running car and shot is pretty cool. If you have Playstation 4 &ndash; you have to get Playstation VR.</li>
<li><strong>Lucky&rsquo;s Tale with Oculus Rift</strong> &ndash; This was just pure joy to play. Being able to lean forward or sideways is surprisingly fulfilling when playing 3D platformer. Looking forward to playing games like SimCity or Civilization.</li>
</ul>


<p>And 3 more demos, that I really liked:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Arch Virtual</strong> &ndash; this is the future of architecture and interior design. Let me just say &ndash; you are inside a kitchen, and with a few gestures you can change colour of wall paint, type of tiles or pick a model of a fridge &ndash; and see in the real time effects of your decisions. This is better than, and will replace construction show rooms.</li>
<li><strong>Budget Cuts</strong> -I was not good at it, so I didn’t enjoyed this game as much. However, I really would like to come back to it. Stealth mode games are perfect fit for VR and this one is very well made. Playing something like Comandos would be great.</li>
<li><strong>Virzoom</strong> &ndash; gym bike + VR. That combination works really well. I expect to see that in the gyms very soon.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you haven’t yet tried latest generation of VR hardware on well made content, like mentioned above &ndash; you have to try.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/tj0Zw2Q0wbE/maxresdefault.jpg" alt="Mind blown" /></p>

<p>Your mind might be blown away and you have to experience it to understand what I mean.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
